<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2404.11683v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:title>Unifying Scene Representation and Hand-Eye Calibration with 3D Foundation Models</ns0:title>
    <ns0:updated>2024-04-17T18:29:32Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.11683v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2404.11683v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf" />
    <ns0:summary>Representing the environment is a central challenge in robotics, and is essential for effective decision-making. Traditionally, before capturing images with a manipulator-mounted camera, users need to calibrate the camera using a specific external marker, such as a checkerboard or AprilTag. However, recent advances in computer vision have led to the development of \emph{3D foundation models}. These are large, pre-trained neural networks that can establish fast and accurate multi-view correspondences with very few images, even in the absence of rich visual features. This paper advocates for the integration of 3D foundation models into scene representation approaches for robotic systems equipped with manipulator-mounted RGB cameras. Specifically, we propose the Joint Calibration and Representation (JCR) method. JCR uses RGB images, captured by a manipulator-mounted camera, to simultaneously construct an environmental representation and calibrate the camera relative to the robot's end-effector, in the absence of specific calibration markers. The resulting 3D environment representation is aligned with the robot's coordinate frame and maintains physically accurate scales. We demonstrate that JCR can build effective scene representations using a low-cost RGB camera attached to a manipulator, without prior calibration.</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:published>2024-04-17T18:29:32Z</ns0:published>
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.RO" />
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Weiming Zhi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Haozhan Tang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tianyi Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Matthew Johnson-Roberson</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
  </ns0:entry>
