<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2410.19115v3</ns0:id>
    <ns0:title>MoGe: Unlocking Accurate Monocular Geometry Estimation for Open-Domain Images with Optimal Training Supervision</ns0:title>
    <ns0:updated>2025-04-15T06:33:45Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.19115v3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2410.19115v3" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf" />
    <ns0:summary>We present MoGe, a powerful model for recovering 3D geometry from monocular open-domain images. Given a single image, our model directly predicts a 3D point map of the captured scene with an affine-invariant representation, which is agnostic to true global scale and shift. This new representation precludes ambiguous supervision in training and facilitate effective geometry learning. Furthermore, we propose a set of novel global and local geometry supervisions that empower the model to learn high-quality geometry. These include a robust, optimal, and efficient point cloud alignment solver for accurate global shape learning, and a multi-scale local geometry loss promoting precise local geometry supervision. We train our model on a large, mixed dataset and demonstrate its strong generalizability and high accuracy. In our comprehensive evaluation on diverse unseen datasets, our model significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods across all tasks, including monocular estimation of 3D point map, depth map, and camera field of view. Code and models can be found on our project page.</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:published>2024-10-24T19:29:02Z</ns0:published>
    <ns1:comment>Project page: https://wangrc.site/MoGePage/</ns1:comment>
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" />
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ruicheng Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sicheng Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Cassie Dai</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jianfeng Xiang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yu Deng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xin Tong</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiaolong Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
  </ns0:entry>
  