<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2411.16877v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:title>PreF3R: Pose-Free Feed-Forward 3D Gaussian Splatting from Variable-length Image Sequence</ns0:title>
    <ns0:updated>2024-11-25T19:16:29Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.16877v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2411.16877v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf" />
    <ns0:summary>We present PreF3R, Pose-Free Feed-forward 3D Reconstruction from an image sequence of variable length. Unlike previous approaches, PreF3R removes the need for camera calibration and reconstructs the 3D Gaussian field within a canonical coordinate frame directly from a sequence of unposed images, enabling efficient novel-view rendering. We leverage DUSt3R's ability for pair-wise 3D structure reconstruction, and extend it to sequential multi-view input via a spatial memory network, eliminating the need for optimization-based global alignment. Additionally, PreF3R incorporates a dense Gaussian parameter prediction head, which enables subsequent novel-view synthesis with differentiable rasterization. This allows supervising our model with the combination of photometric loss and pointmap regression loss, enhancing both photorealism and structural accuracy. Given a sequence of ordered images, PreF3R incrementally reconstructs the 3D Gaussian field at 20 FPS, therefore enabling real-time novel-view rendering. Empirical experiments demonstrate that PreF3R is an effective solution for the challenging task of pose-free feed-forward novel-view synthesis, while also exhibiting robust generalization to unseen scenes.</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:published>2024-11-25T19:16:29Z</ns0:published>
    <ns1:comment>project page: https://computationalrobotics.seas.harvard.edu/PreF3R/</ns1:comment>
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" />
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zequn Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiezhi Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Heng Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
  </ns0:entry>
  