<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2412.19518v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:title>Dust to Tower: Coarse-to-Fine Photo-Realistic Scene Reconstruction from Sparse Uncalibrated Images</ns0:title>
    <ns0:updated>2024-12-27T08:19:34Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.19518v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2412.19518v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf" />
    <ns0:summary>Photo-realistic scene reconstruction from sparse-view, uncalibrated images is highly required in practice. Although some successes have been made, existing methods are either Sparse-View but require accurate camera parameters (i.e., intrinsic and extrinsic), or SfM-free but need densely captured images. To combine the advantages of both methods while addressing their respective weaknesses, we propose Dust to Tower (D2T), an accurate and efficient coarse-to-fine framework to optimize 3DGS and image poses simultaneously from sparse and uncalibrated images. Our key idea is to first construct a coarse model efficiently and subsequently refine it using warped and inpainted images at novel viewpoints. To do this, we first introduce a Coarse Construction Module (CCM) which exploits a fast Multi-View Stereo model to initialize a 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) and recover initial camera poses. To refine the 3D model at novel viewpoints, we propose a Confidence Aware Depth Alignment (CADA) module to refine the coarse depth maps by aligning their confident parts with estimated depths by a Mono-depth model. Then, a Warped Image-Guided Inpainting (WIGI) module is proposed to warp the training images to novel viewpoints by the refined depth maps, and inpainting is applied to fulfill the ``holes" in the warped images caused by view-direction changes, providing high-quality supervision to further optimize the 3D model and the camera poses. Extensive experiments and ablation studies demonstrate the validity of D2T and its design choices, achieving state-of-the-art performance in both tasks of novel view synthesis and pose estimation while keeping high efficiency. Codes will be publicly available.</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:published>2024-12-27T08:19:34Z</ns0:published>
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" />
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xudong Cai</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yongcai Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhaoxin Fan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Deng Haoran</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shuo Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wanting Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Deying Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Lun Luo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Minhang Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jintao Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
  </ns0:entry>
