<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2412.07746v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:title>LoRA3D: Low-Rank Self-Calibration of 3D Geometric Foundation Models</ns0:title>
    <ns0:updated>2024-12-10T18:45:04Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.07746v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2412.07746v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf" />
    <ns0:summary>Emerging 3D geometric foundation models, such as DUSt3R, offer a promising approach for in-the-wild 3D vision tasks. However, due to the high-dimensional nature of the problem space and scarcity of high-quality 3D data, these pre-trained models still struggle to generalize to many challenging circumstances, such as limited view overlap or low lighting. To address this, we propose LoRA3D, an efficient self-calibration pipeline to $\textit{specialize}$ the pre-trained models to target scenes using their own multi-view predictions. Taking sparse RGB images as input, we leverage robust optimization techniques to refine multi-view predictions and align them into a global coordinate frame. In particular, we incorporate prediction confidence into the geometric optimization process, automatically re-weighting the confidence to better reflect point estimation accuracy. We use the calibrated confidence to generate high-quality pseudo labels for the calibrating views and use low-rank adaptation (LoRA) to fine-tune the models on the pseudo-labeled data. Our method does not require any external priors or manual labels. It completes the self-calibration process on a $\textbf{single standard GPU within just 5 minutes}$. Each low-rank adapter requires only $\textbf{18MB}$ of storage. We evaluated our method on $\textbf{more than 160 scenes}$ from the Replica, TUM and Waymo Open datasets, achieving up to $\textbf{88% performance improvement}$ on 3D reconstruction, multi-view pose estimation and novel-view rendering.</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:published>2024-12-10T18:45:04Z</ns0:published>
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" />
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ziqi Lu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Heng Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Danfei Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Boyi Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Boris Ivanovic</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Marco Pavone</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yue Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
  </ns0:entry>
  