<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06336v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:title>MEt3R: Measuring Multi-View Consistency in Generated Images</ns0:title>
    <ns0:updated>2026-02-21T20:55:29Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.06336v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2501.06336v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf" />
    <ns0:summary>We introduce MEt3R, a metric for multi-view consistency in generated images. Large-scale generative models for multi-view image generation are rapidly advancing the field of 3D inference from sparse observations. However, due to the nature of generative modeling, traditional reconstruction metrics are not suitable to measure the quality of generated outputs and metrics that are independent of the sampling procedure are desperately needed. In this work, we specifically address the aspect of consistency between generated multi-view images, which can be evaluated independently of the specific scene. Our approach uses DUSt3R to obtain dense 3D reconstructions from image pairs in a feed-forward manner, which are used to warp image contents from one view into the other. Then, feature maps of these images are compared to obtain a similarity score that is invariant to view-dependent effects. Using MEt3R, we evaluate the consistency of a large set of previous methods for novel view and video generation, including our open, multi-view latent diffusion model.</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:published>2025-01-10T20:43:33Z</ns0:published>
    <ns1:comment>Project website: https://geometric-rl.mpi-inf.mpg.de/met3r/ Updated to Camera-Ready version</ns1:comment>
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" />
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mohammad Asim</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Christopher Wewer</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Thomas Wimmer</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Bernt Schiele</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jan Eric Lenssen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
  </ns0:entry>
