<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13928v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:title>Fast3R: Towards 3D Reconstruction of 1000+ Images in One Forward Pass</ns0:title>
    <ns0:updated>2025-03-19T19:35:52Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13928v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2501.13928v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf" />
    <ns0:summary>Multi-view 3D reconstruction remains a core challenge in computer vision, particularly in applications requiring accurate and scalable representations across diverse perspectives. Current leading methods such as DUSt3R employ a fundamentally pairwise approach, processing images in pairs and necessitating costly global alignment procedures to reconstruct from multiple views. In this work, we propose Fast 3D Reconstruction (Fast3R), a novel multi-view generalization to DUSt3R that achieves efficient and scalable 3D reconstruction by processing many views in parallel. Fast3R's Transformer-based architecture forwards N images in a single forward pass, bypassing the need for iterative alignment. Through extensive experiments on camera pose estimation and 3D reconstruction, Fast3R demonstrates state-of-the-art performance, with significant improvements in inference speed and reduced error accumulation. These results establish Fast3R as a robust alternative for multi-view applications, offering enhanced scalability without compromising reconstruction accuracy.</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.GR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:published>2025-01-23T18:59:55Z</ns0:published>
    <ns1:comment>CVPR 2025. Project website: https://fast3r-3d.github.io/</ns1:comment>
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" />
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jianing Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Alexander Sax</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kevin J. Liang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mikael Henaff</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Hao Tang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ang Cao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Joyce Chai</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Franziska Meier</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Matt Feiszli</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
  </ns0:entry>
  