<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.12356v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:title>Regist3R: Incremental Registration with Stereo Foundation Model</ns0:title>
    <ns0:updated>2025-09-15T15:35:27Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.12356v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.12356v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf" />
    <ns0:summary>Multi-view 3D reconstruction has remained an essential yet challenging problem in the field of computer vision. While DUSt3R and its successors have achieved breakthroughs in 3D reconstruction from unposed images, these methods exhibit significant limitations when scaling to multi-view scenarios, including high computational cost and cumulative error induced by global alignment. To address these challenges, we propose Regist3R, a novel stereo foundation model tailored for efficient and scalable incremental reconstruction. Regist3R leverages an incremental reconstruction paradigm, enabling large-scale 3D reconstructions from unordered and many-view image collections. We evaluate Regist3R on public datasets for camera pose estimation and 3D reconstruction. Our experiments demonstrate that Regist3R achieves comparable performance with optimization-based methods while significantly improving computational efficiency, and outperforms existing multi-view reconstruction models. Furthermore, to assess its performance in real-world applications, we introduce a challenging oblique aerial dataset which has long spatial spans and hundreds of views. The results highlight the effectiveness of Regist3R. We also demonstrate the first attempt to reconstruct large-scale scenes encompassing over thousands of views through pointmap-based foundation models, showcasing its potential for practical applications in large-scale 3D reconstruction tasks, including urban modeling, aerial mapping, and beyond.</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:published>2025-04-16T02:46:53Z</ns0:published>
    <ns1:comment>Accepted by ACM Multimedia 2025. github link: https://github.com/Liu-SD/Regist3R</ns1:comment>
    <ns1:primary_category term="eess.IV" />
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sidun Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wenyu Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Peng Qiao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yong Dou</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
  </ns0:entry>
  