<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.03129v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:title>GraphSeg: Segmented 3D Representations via Graph Edge Addition and Contraction</ns0:title>
    <ns0:updated>2025-04-04T02:42:45Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.03129v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.03129v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf" />
    <ns0:summary>Robots operating in unstructured environments often require accurate and consistent object-level representations. This typically requires segmenting individual objects from the robot's surroundings. While recent large models such as Segment Anything (SAM) offer strong performance in 2D image segmentation. These advances do not translate directly to performance in the physical 3D world, where they often over-segment objects and fail to produce consistent mask correspondences across views. In this paper, we present GraphSeg, a framework for generating consistent 3D object segmentations from a sparse set of 2D images of the environment without any depth information. GraphSeg adds edges to graphs and constructs dual correspondence graphs: one from 2D pixel-level similarities and one from inferred 3D structure. We formulate segmentation as a problem of edge addition, then subsequent graph contraction, which merges multiple 2D masks into unified object-level segmentations. We can then leverage \emph{3D foundation models} to produce segmented 3D representations. GraphSeg achieves robust segmentation with significantly fewer images and greater accuracy than prior methods. We demonstrate state-of-the-art performance on tabletop scenes and show that GraphSeg enables improved performance on downstream robotic manipulation tasks. Code available at https://github.com/tomtang502/graphseg.git.</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:published>2025-04-04T02:42:45Z</ns0:published>
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.RO" />
    <ns1:journal_ref>Proceedings of the IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2026</ns1:journal_ref>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Haozhan Tang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tianyi Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Oliver Kroemer</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Matthew Johnson-Roberson</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Weiming Zhi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
  </ns0:entry>
  