<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.16290v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:title>Dens3R: A Foundation Model for 3D Geometry Prediction</ns0:title>
    <ns0:updated>2025-07-22T07:22:30Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.16290v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.16290v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf" />
    <ns0:summary>Recent advances in dense 3D reconstruction have led to significant progress, yet achieving accurate unified geometric prediction remains a major challenge. Most existing methods are limited to predicting a single geometry quantity from input images. However, geometric quantities such as depth, surface normals, and point maps are inherently correlated, and estimating them in isolation often fails to ensure consistency, thereby limiting both accuracy and practical applicability. This motivates us to explore a unified framework that explicitly models the structural coupling among different geometric properties to enable joint regression. In this paper, we present Dens3R, a 3D foundation model designed for joint geometric dense prediction and adaptable to a wide range of downstream tasks. Dens3R adopts a two-stage training framework to progressively build a pointmap representation that is both generalizable and intrinsically invariant. Specifically, we design a lightweight shared encoder-decoder backbone and introduce position-interpolated rotary positional encoding to maintain expressive power while enhancing robustness to high-resolution inputs. By integrating image-pair matching features with intrinsic invariance modeling, Dens3R accurately regresses multiple geometric quantities such as surface normals and depth, achieving consistent geometry perception from single-view to multi-view inputs. Additionally, we propose a post-processing pipeline that supports geometrically consistent multi-view inference. Extensive experiments demonstrate the superior performance of Dens3R across various dense 3D prediction tasks and highlight its potential for broader applications.</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:published>2025-07-22T07:22:30Z</ns0:published>
    <ns1:comment>Project Page: https://g-1nonly.github.io/Dens3R/, Code: https://github.com/G-1nOnly/Dens3R</ns1:comment>
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" />
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xianze Fang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jingnan Gao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhe Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhuo Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xingyu Ren</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiangjing Lyu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Qiaomu Ren</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhonglei Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiaokang Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yichao Yan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chengfei Lyu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
  </ns0:entry>
  